# PAVEL PETRASYUK

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## PROFILE

Software Engineer with a passion for frontend and a strong focus on Intuitive UI and UX. Specialized in JavaScript (ES6+), React, Redux, TypeScript, RESTful architecture, Node/Express, Python.

email: ppavel0822@gmail.com // linkedin: devpavel // portfolio: pashatay.herokuapp.com

#### EDUCATION

Introduction to Computer Science Harvard University 2019

Bachelor of Economics MUH, Moscow 2011 - 2015

#### SKILLS

#### //Front-end

JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js (Router, Context, Hooks), Redux, Enzyme, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, Webpack, Babel, Gulp.js, Chart.js

#### //Back-end

Node.js, Express.js PostgreSQL, PLSQL MongoDB, Mongoose, RESTful Architecture, Mocha & Chai, JWT, Python

#### //Dev-tools

Git, Github, Heroku, Chrome Dev Tools, Travis CI

#### INTERESTS

Songwriting Cooking Reading(Fyodor Dostoyevsky) Hiking

# EXPERIENCE

## **PROJECTS**

**Dream.log** Software engineer | New York | 2020

# demo | client-side repo | server-side repo

Full-stack web application. Dream journal/blog.

- Designed App Architecture & Constructed a PostgreSQL database to handle relationship between users and data, aiding logical organization of records while enforcing ACID compliance ensuring stability and predictability of data
- Built Node.js server integrating Express RESTful architecture by designing semantic routes and middleware to modularize the request-response allowing for easy configuration of additional features
- Stored bcrypt-encrypted user passwords in a database by randomizing salt rounds in order to ensure data consistency
- Built client-site web API by leveraging reusable components in React.js to dynamically render pages with varying user data
- Developed UX/UI by making it fully responsive for mobile devices using media queries in vanilla CSS
- Exploited Chart.js library to visualize users data as a part of the app functionality

**Bestie** Software engineer | New York | 2019

## <u>demo | client-side repo | server-side repo</u>

Full-stack web application. A birthday reminder.

- Engineered a Node/Express server by creating custom middleware to handle authentication, session management, and serving static assets, decoupling server logic and maintaining a modularized and clean database
- Utilized Nodemailer, Handlebarsand Cron to implement email notifications functionality
- Implemented JWTs by generating bearer tokens and validating a user session by caching the required credentials in order to optimize the number of requests made to the database, resulting in faster server response time and improved scalability
- Implemented unit testing using Mocha/Chai and SuperTest module

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Front-end Web Developer Litanin.com | New York | 2019 - Present

- Built reusableReact Modules to supplement new features of the project
- Optimized design of web pages for smartphones and tablets to improve responsiveness and user experience by using CSS3
- Used JavaScript to design the logic of web applications
- Collaborated with other team members and participated in code reviews

# **Software Project Manager** Credit Europe Bank | Moscow | 2011 - 2015

- Managed internal software projects
- Created project schedules and supervised a group of five engineers
- Created documentation and maintained project plan throughout project execution
- Acted as a liaison between the IT department and senior management